Welcome to the video on addressing Amazon's multiple accounts policy
violations.
This video covers the following topics; 1.
What can you do to
address violations?
2.
Best practices to remain compliant.
The content in this
video applies to all stores.
Let us first understand how you can respond to a
violation notice.
If you receive a notification that a related account has
been deactivated, this means that one of your existing accounts violated Amazon's
policies.
In order to reactivate your related account, you must first address
the violation in the underlying account that was responsible for the policy
violations by submitting an appeal for each violation.
You can appeal by signing
into the account that was responsible for the policy violations.
You must appeal
in each regional Amazon store in which the account has been deactivated for the
policy violation.
You can submit your appeal by accessing your account health
dashboard.
If your appeal for the underlying account that was responsible
for the policy violations is accepted and the account is successfully reactivated,
you can then appeal your related account.
When submitting the appeal, you will need
to provide us with the storefront name of the original account that was reactivated
and the date of reactivation.
Use case number one.
You own two selling accounts,
seller storefront one, and seller storefront two.
Seller storefront one
receives a deactivation notice for directing customers to an external site
circumventing the sales process.
You then receive a deactivation notice on
seller storefront two since it is related to seller storefront one.
You should log
into your seller storefront one account and appeal the violation.
If your appeal
is accepted and the seller storefront one account is successfully reactivated,
then log into your seller storefront two account and appeal through the
account health dashboard by providing the storefront name of the original
account that was reactivated and the date of reactivation.
If you believe the
related account deactivation happened in error or you have never owned or
operated another account, please submit an appeal through the account health
dashboard and confirm that the account is not related to yours.
If we do not
receive evidence confirming the account is not related to you, the account will
not be reinstated.
If you previously co-owned or co-operated the underlying
account with a former business partner, you would need to provide supporting
documentation such as a contract showing separation of the business relationship
as part of the appeal.
Please note that it's against policy to buy, sell, or
transfer your account to or from another seller.
Let us learn about the best
practices to remain compliant.
Sellers who have a legitimate business reason for
operating more than one account and maintain all accounts in good standing
will not be at risk for a multiple accounts deactivation.
Please make sure
you only create additional accounts if there is a valid business reason.
Examples
of valid business reasons include owning separate brands with different
storefront names or selling products manufactured by different companies.
When
you receive notices or see alerts on your account health dashboard or
performance notifications from Amazon that indicate you are violating Amazon
selling policies, please correct the behavior and submit an appeal if applicable
as soon as possible.
Opening a new account instead of addressing the
underlying violations within your existing accounts is a violation of
Amazon's policies and will only trigger an automatic deactivation on your
related accounts.
All sellers are responsible for understanding and
adhering to the terms and conditions set out by Amazon's business solutions
agreement which is part of the registration process and includes the
selling policies and seller code of conduct.
All sellers are expected to
maintain and keep secure their own account information and credentials.
In
the primary account information, sellers should not list information of any
third-party services they may be using to help manage the account.
However, if
you have engaged a valid third-party service, we recommend listing them as a
secondary user in the approved app Users User Permissions.
We hope this video on
our multiple accounts policy was helpful.
Thank you and happy selling on Amazon!